Now you learned all the theory about how components work, how you pass data around, how props work and
imdi, bileenler nasl iitme yardmclar ie yaryor ve bylece devam ettiklerini anlatan tm
so on
teorileri reneceksiniz.
and that's all nice but how do you actually plan a react application,
Ve hepsi gzel, fakat nasl bir yeniden hareket uygulamas planlyorsunuz.
how does that work?
Bu nasl alyor.
Now you can of course split this up into more granular steps than these three
Artk elbette bunu daha ayrntl admlara ayrp daha sonra cretsiz yapabilirsiniz.
but here are three very important steps I see and I regularly go through when planning a react application.
Ancak burada  nemli adm var ve bir tekrar uygulama bavurusu planlarken dzenli olarak geiyorum.
The first step is planning the component tree, the component structure,
lk adm, bileen bileen yapsn planlamaktr.
you probably get a design by your designer or you basically created an app design on your own and now
kendi bana bir uygulama tasarm oluturmanzdr ve imdi bunu yeniden eyleme bileenlere blmek size aittir.
it's up to you to split this up into react components
Muhtemelen tasarmc tarafndan tasarlanm olmanz ya da temelde
and it's absolutely normal that the results you may have at the end might look different than your initially
Sonunda elde edeceiniz sonularn, balangta planlanan bileeninizden farkl grnebilecei kesinlikle normaldir,
planned component tree but it's super important to have an idea about what should go into its own component
ancak kendi bileenine nelerin girmesi gerektii konusunda bir fikir edinmek
and what not.
son derece nemlidir.
The other important part of your application of course is the application state,
Bavurunuzun nemli ksm tabii ki uygulama halidir.
you can also translate this with the data you plan on using and manipulating in your application. For example
rnein, uygulamanzda kullanmay planladnz verilere sahip tm evirmenleri grebilirsiniz ve
and of course you will do this over the next lectures, in our burger application,
tabii Bergere bavurunuzdaki bir sonraki derslerde bunu yapacaksnz.
we need to keep track about the ingredients a user added because that will determine what we need to
bu, ne sunmamz gerektiini ve nihayetinde kullancnn ne demesi gerektiini belirleyecektir.
render and also what the user needs to pay at the end.
Bir kullancnn ekledii ierikleri takip etmemiz gerekmektedir; nk
Now once you know the component structure of your application and the state you're going to use in it, you
imdi, uygulamanzn ayrmasn ve yapsn bildikten sonra onu kullanacanza deinmek iin
can plan components versus containers.
bileenleri konteynerlere gre planlayamazsnz.
So which components in your application should be stateless or functional,
Bylece uygulamanzdaki hangi bileenlerin stateless veya ilevsel olmas gerektii.
sometimes also referred to as dumb components and which components have to be stateful components
Bazen aptal bileenler olarak da adlandrlr ve hangi snfn anahtar szcyle oluturulmu olan
created with that class keyword because they need to manage some state and distribute it down to their
devletin tam bileenleri olmas gereken bileenlerin bir ksm ynetilmeli ve onlarn daha
dumber components, to the stateless components.
az bileenleri halinde kendi iren bileenlerine datlmaldr.
These are the three steps I regularly go through and these are the steps I want to go through with you together.
Bunlar dzenli olarak getiim  adm ve bunlar gabber ile gemek istediim admlar.
We're going to plan our component tree, component structure and then we're going to have a look at which
Bileen bileenlerimizin yapsn planlayacaz ve sonra hangi dzeye ihtiyacmz olduunu ve bir
state we need and what can be a component and what should be a container
bileen ve ne olmas gerektiini bir gz atacaz.
and then we're just going to start building the application.
Sonra da uygulamay oluturmaya balayacaz.
And as you will see we might then even add more components than we initially planned because we see that
Grdnz gibi balangta planladmzdan daha fazla bileen ekleyebiliriz, nk biz daha
we can split up even more
da ayrlabildiimizi grrz.
or maybe that some split
Veya belki de bu biraz blnmlktr.
we did plan doesn't make sense once we start implementing it and that's perfectly normal.
Plan yaptk, onu uygulamaya baladktan sonra mantkl deil ve bu tamamen normaldir.
But having a plan is of course very important.
Ancak tabii ki bir plana sahip olmak ok nemlidir.